# Eric Iyen

Johnson City, TN emanny0018@gmail.com 423-676-2604

Exceptionally skilled and dependable Field Test Engineer with an In-depth knowledge and experience in software testing and troubleshooting able to compete in varying environment where I can employ my knowledge and skills. Strong multitasker able to address simultaneous project needs and concerns with complete professionalism and accuracy. Adept at managing subordinate technical teams of varying sizes.

#readytowork

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

# Work Experience

#### **IT Technician**

Dell Technologies - Johnson City, TN June 2020 to Present

- Perform basic installation service (Client System; CPU only)
- De-Installation of Legacy CPU
- Win 10 Upgrade
- As Needed Services Deskside Application Load
- Peer-to Peer Data Migration
- Redeployment of Legacy System (CPU and Monitor)

#### **Drive Test Engineer**

Exagen Inc.

January 2020 to April 2020

- Performed RF Drive Test activities on pre-defined sites within a specified location with supported networks as VoLTE, LTE, 4G, 3G and UMTS technology
- Able to perform various types of mobility and stationary RF test cases in the field of LTE, WCDMA, UMTS, and GSM.
- Performed SVT and Non -Emergency E911 calls to Dispatchers for accurate location and exact phase of call
- Able to manipulate GPS, Google Earth, to drive round and park properly for testing.

## **E911 Drive Tester (Sprint Project)**

TELNET INC - Rockville, MD January 2019 to May 2019

Performed CSFB testing to verify LTE call success rate and call drop rate, speed-test & F011

• Able to perform site walks/drive tests for pre-construction SINR verification, and recommend macro site change.

- Performed RF Drive Test activities on pre-defined sites within a specified location with supported networks as VoLTE, LTE, 4G, 3G and UMTS technology
- Analyzed and Measured LTE parameters like RSRP, RSSI, RSRQ, SINR and CQI Measurement.
- Able to manipulate GPS, Google Earth, to drive round and park properly for testing.
- Performed Stationary test at the cell sites to check/verify the throughput (DL/UL)
- Updated daily schedule and route with Project manager

# **RF Drive test Engineer**

AIRTEL NIGERIA LTD

October 2016 to September 2017

Performed drive testing for LTE/4G site verification and troubleshooting using X-CAL.

- Collect radio measurements like RSRP, SINR and PCI.
- · Handover testing and troubleshooting, Downlink and Uplink throughput testing

Data collection of Optimization for GSM, UMTS, CDMA, and LTE networks using XCAL software.

- Prepare cluster and cell wise CS & PS, KPI report
- · Exhibit excellent troubleshooting skills whenever issues arise during the data

collection drive.

- Performing CW and CCW drive around the site to check for swap sectors and successful handovers between sectors within a site
- Performed E911 PSAP call testing with two different phones monitoring all three

sectors and conforming the correct LAT/LONG.

- Performed pre and post migration cluster drives.
- Performed Stationary test at the cell sites to check/verify the throughput (DL/UL)
- Performed attach/detach tests and ping tests.

#### RF Engineer

Network-Concept Nig. Ltd

December 2015 to October 2016

Furnished technical issue resolution support to engineering department.

- Performed UMTS&LTE Drive testing using XCAL wireless network
- Oversaw self-design project management and upgrading.
- Prepared and submitted schematic diagrams and testing procedures to management.
- Prepared and submitted RF coverage analysis outlines.
- Designed all systems to adhere to local state and federal safety standards and rules.
- Oversaw technical teams and provided guidance and feedback as needed.

#### **Revenue Collector**

Oredo Local Government Area (Nigeria)

July 2015 to December 2015

Performed various tax data Informations, and maintaining accurate tax records in a digitalized system

- Determine appropriate methods of debt settlement, such as offers of compromise, wage garnishment, or seizure and sale of property.
- Examine and analyze tax assets and liabilities to determine resolution of delinquent tax problems.

## **Drive Test Engineer**

Exagen Solutions - Watervliet, NY January 2020

- Performed RF Drive Test activities on pre-defined sites within a specified location with supported networks as VoLTE, LTE, 4G, 3G and UMTS technology
- Able to perform various types of mobility and stationary RF test cases in the field of LTE, WCDMA, UMTS, and GSM.
- Performed SVT and Non -Emergency E911 calls to Dispatchers for accurate location and exact phase of call
- Able to manipulate GPS, Google Earth, to drive round and park properly for testing.

## Education

## **B.sc in Medical Physiology**

AMBROSE ALLI UNIVERSITY (Edo State

February 2009 to April 2014

## Skills

- Rf
- QXDM
- Mobile Device Testing
- Database administration
- Database
- Customer support
- Xml
- Unit testing
- Emergency response
- Microsoft word
- Word
- Autocad
- Logging
- · Problem-solving
- 4G/LTE
- 3G
- SQL
- Test Cases

# Certifications and Licenses

#### driver's license

#### **HIPAA**

June 2020 to June 2022

Hipaa Security

Hippa Awareness for Helathcare Providers

# Additional Information

#### SKILLS:

- Good interpersonal and observational skills
- Mobile Drive Test Experience
- Wide breadth of RF measurement experience
- Good knowledge of digital and analog electronics
- Sound XCAL, QXDM skills
- Hipaa Security and awareness
- Tracking, Logging & Reporting
- Good understanding and ability to work with XML
- Great customer support skills
- General Database administration
- System & Unit Testing
- High critical thinking and problem-solving skills
- Sound organizational and management abilities
- Strong oral and written communication skills
- Computer literacy in Microsoft Word and AutoCAD
- Emergency Response, Firefighting, First Aid Risk Assessment skills